Childhood is strange.
童年是十分奇怪的
Strange enough to make you question whether or not it really happened.
奇怪到对于那时发生与否的事，你都会无尽的怀疑
It's full of awkward new experiences,
那时你经历过很多尴尬的新经历
LGR小时候==>
bizarre conversations,
问过很多奇奇怪怪的为什么
and enough unusual perspectives to make you wonder if half of it was real.
还有过很多超乎常理的想象，兴许有一半已经实现了吧
Then you run across something at a thrift store or online, and you go "Huh!"
后来你去淘二手，或是网购的时候，你看到了熟悉的东西
"So I *wasn't just making that up!"
你眼前一亮：“哇，原来小的时候我真的见过诶！”
Take for example Waterful Ring-Toss by Tomy in 1976.
诸如这个1976年生产的水中套圈玩具
I stumbled into this particular example at a local Goodwill several years ago,
我几年前去淘二手的时候，不知为何看到了这个
and instantly some long-forgotten part of my brain bolted awake and about coughed up a lung.
然后我那些早已忘记的事，又回忆了起来，让我述说不止
All of sudden, I *knew* that I had this as a kid,
突然间，我才回过味来，我小时候玩过啊
that I played it entirely too much for my own good,
在我那时我有的玩具中，我玩这个的频率最高
and that I now questioned whether or not I was crazy for having done so.
然后我想，那时的我为什么死盯这一个玩具不放呢:-P
Tomy Waterful Ring-Toss is a handheld tabletop game that requires the use of water to work.
这种手持水中套圈玩具需要装很多水才能用
Otherwise, it's just a dry container filled with air and little plastic rings.
否则，它就是一个装有几个小塑料环的无聊干涸
Sure, you can play the game without any water,
当然，没水玩也是可以的
but that's just about as enjoyable as shaking out the last few Cheerios
但这跟就集齐那些永远收集不齐的
stuck in the folds of the plastic bag at the bottom of a box of cereal.
干脆面附赠卡片一样没有意思
But once you fill this beast up with water,
但当你往其装水后
it transforms into a finely tuned machine
这个玩具娱乐小朋友的功能就完全放开了
of childhood mental engagement.
Or at least that's the idea.
至少我觉得是这样的
Really, it's *just* interesting enough to shut up a five-year-old on a short road trip,
说真的，要让小朋友在路上不吵不闹的话，这玩意挺管用的
at least until they have to pee or the container spills onto the back seat,
直到他们要去上厕所，或是将里面的水给倒了出来
whichever comes first.
这两件事总有一件会先发生的:-P
The latter of which was quite likely if you'd lost the cap that goes over the filling hole,
后者经常是因为用来封住灌水口的盖子给弄丢了
like I have with this one.
比如我这台
Waterful Ring-Toss is less of a game and more of a test of skill.
这玩意要我说，不像个游戏，而像个能力测试
And patience. Lots of patience.
并且需要很多很多耐心
Because water and floaty rings don't exactly make for movements of precision and calculation.
因为水流和漂浮于此的塑料环的运动没有规律可言
I guess you could say that success is a complete "toss up"
所以说，这玩意的“输赢”完全凭运气
that really puts you through the "ringer."
而正是这种运气导向让你爱不释手
But, oh, "water" relief once you finally win!
可当你赢的时候，水就倒了出来:-(
You simply push in the plastic button
你仅需不停按压下面的塑料按键
and the plastic rings will be shot upward inside the plastic container,
然后塑料环就在水里被射了上去
where the goal is to secure them onto plastic spikes.
目标是将这些塑料环推进塑料尖状物
It's a ring-toss carnival came in a portable form factor,
这就是路边套环游戏的便携版
and it's actually pretty genius, in a way.
在某种程度上，挺巧妙的
It doesn't require batteries,
这玩意不需要装电池
there are no electronic parts or anything mechanical that can jam up,
因为没有什么电子玩意，也没有容易卡住的机械装置
there wasn't a pile of pieces to lose, and most of all, it was cheap.
也没有一大堆容易脱落，丢失的部件，更重要的是，它很便宜
So at least in terms of children's games and games on the go,
所以至少对于便携的儿童玩具来说
this was automatically better than LCD games,
这玩意绝对比LCD屏幕游戏，电子玩偶
注：BV1Cs411f7aM 喷神 EP113 老虎牌游戏机 @ 喷神9课
electromechanical handhelds,
jigsaw puzzles and travel-size board games.
还是一大堆拼图或是便携纸牌游戏啥的好多了
Well, "better" from the perspective of parents who had less to worry about,
好吧，对家长来说，这玩意只要别把
other than the risk of spilling water.
里面的水倒出来，基本啥也不用担心了
And, hey, if you were a kid with nothing else–
对于小孩来说，要是啥也没得玩......
Superbart：现在的小朋友真是太幸运了，我小时侯有意义的玩具
就是一堆积木和五年级买的电脑。再看看现在，Pad和手机绚烂的世界真是无法想象啊
and I mean NOTHING else to play–
真的除这个，啥也没得玩的话
then this was freakin' awesome.
这东西真是很有趣呢:-P
If anything the endearing little noises it made when using it made the whole thing worthwhile.
而且玩的时候发出的声音，让我觉得更加值回票价
And then there was the thrill of finally getting all those rings onto the pegs that was...
然后最终把所有塑料环套在尖刺后的欢乐就......
...negligible.
......没啥可说了:-P
But, hey, as a kid, it was something to accomplish and occupy yourself with for a while.
可作为小孩呢，这件事好歹能吸引你，让你稍微满足一下
And that was really all that five-year-old me wanted.
对于五岁的我来说，这就够了
At least until my curiosity got the best of me
然后我强烈的好奇心驱使我
and I swiped my dad's screwdriver to take thing apart to see how it worked.
“偷”了我爸的螺丝刀，拆开玩具，看看原理
Ah, yes, just as I suspected:
然后正如我所想
magic!
真是魔法啊:-P
So I know these things existed and that I owned one,
我现在想起来，我见过，也有过一台
but two questions remain:
但我还有两个问题：
What happened to mine and which model did I have?
我的那台最后怎么样了，我有的那台是啥样式的？
Well, the answer to the first question is most likely
第一个问题好说，我要不是搞坏了他
Superbart: 我看到了我的未来吗？
that I either destroyed it when trying to take it apart,
or that it ended up languishing on the shelves of a thrift store in Kernersville.
要不就在某个附近的二手店孤独终老
The answer to the second question is more vague,
然而第二个问题有点难以回答了
seeing as there was an entire line of these things
因为这玩意是一系列的，通称"Waterfuls"系列
known as Waterfuls.
They were sold by Tomy, Milton Bradley, Coleco and probably others,
由很多玩具厂商生产，还有很多种类，我没法说啊
and has dozens of variants, so there's no telling.
I highly doubt it was this 1976 original because...
我觉得我那台不是1976的原版
frick, I wasn't even born until a decade later.
因为我在十年后才出生呢
Whatever the answer truly is,
但无论我的那台是怎样的
these Waterful toys hold a special place in my heart.
这个玩具在我的心目中，有特殊的地位
The place where I just can't wait for us to get where we're going
小时候在路上等烦的时候，我拿出来玩玩
so I can just get out of the car and do anything else,
然后我可以安然下车，干点别的
because these stupid rings are startin' to really get on my nerves!
因为这点破圈圈真的想要诅咒我啊:-(
本片由SuperBart翻译,原作者LGR上传于2015年2月23日
不知道各位的童年是彩色的还是灰白的？我觉得很多人是两者兼有吧
字幕下载：github.com/BenderBolg/Subtitles
支持原作者：patreon.com/LazyGameReviews​
And if you enjoyed this look back at Waterful Ring-Toss,
如果你喜欢这个视频的话
and would like to see some others?
为何不想看看其他的呢？
I guess. I don't–I don't have any more, but
然而，类似视频我还真没有多少
maybe I'll get some more.
兴许以后我会多作些
Then, uh, don't sub to my channel, 'cause like I said, I don't have any.
要是你只想看这种类型的话，我不太建议你订阅
But if you want to see some other videos on *other* things that I have done,
如果你想找更多我制作的视频的话
and I've done quite a lot of them– mostly video games and computers and such–
我也确实有很多，大多数是关于游戏和电脑啥的
then definitely subscribe if you would like to be notified when there are more of them.
那你就订阅吧，有新视频会有提醒的
You can also tweet me on Twitter and book my face on Facebook
你也可以在Twitter和Facebook上找到我
for other updates throughout the week, as well as do the whole Patreon thing.
来关注我的一周，在Patreon也一样
And if you're not sure what that is, then just click the "P" right there and go check it out!
如果你还不明白的话，点击上面的"P"键你就明白了
It lets you support the show, as well as get some extra perks.
在哪里，你可以支持我，也可以看到独家视频
And as always, thank you very much for watching.
最后，一如继往，感谢大家收看！